<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://azurebrian.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://azurebrian.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-19T08:16:51-05:00</updated><id>https://azurebrian.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Azure Brian</title><subtitle>My musings, and sometimes confessions, on the journey to becoming an Azure architect.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Find Machines Vulnerable to Print Nightmare and Remediate</title><link href="https://azurebrian.com/security/blue%20team/2021/10/18/Remediate-PrintNightmare.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Find Machines Vulnerable to Print Nightmare and Remediate" /><published>2021-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-10-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://azurebrian.com/security/blue%20team/2021/10/18/Remediate-PrintNightmare</id><author><name></name></author><category term="security" /><category term="blue team" /><summary type="html">It’s been a while, and boy was it a Spring/Summer to remember regarding Microsoft vulnerabilities. Print Nightmare (CVE-2021-34527) scared me enough to want to ensure I went “blue team” enough to prevent any infection. So, I crafted a somewhat crude, but effective, script to detect and remediate on the machines I had influence over. You can find the script in my Github repo. You’ll notice right at the top that my intention was to disable the print spooler service altogether where I could get away with it. Of course, on user machines that’s a little more difficult and hence the trouble to detect and remediate those machines. Anyway, this is pretty short and to the point I guess, so I won’t belabor any unnecessary details. Please have a look and feel free to drop a comment regarding any similar solutions you might have come up with. And feel free to download, mod, and even open a PR if you like.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Folding@home With Your Spare Azure Credits</title><link href="https://azurebrian.com/how-to/2020/06/30/Folding-With-Azure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Folding@home With Your Spare Azure Credits" /><published>2020-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-06-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://azurebrian.com/how-to/2020/06/30/Folding-With-Azure</id><author><name>Brian Davis</name></author><category term="how-to" /><category term="folding@home" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Stored Access Policies For Azure Files</title><link href="https://azurebrian.com/how-to/2020/05/11/Stored-Access-Policies-For-Azure-Files.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stored Access Policies For Azure Files" /><published>2020-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-05-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://azurebrian.com/how-to/2020/05/11/Stored-Access-Policies-For-Azure-Files</id><author><name>Brian Davis</name></author><category term="how-to" /><category term="storage" /><category term="files" /><summary type="html">Lately, at work, I’ve been helping to lead an implementation of an Azure Files share for a client. This is the second client we’ve set up with one, and it’s a pretty elegant solution that mitigates the need for an on-prem file server. It’s also available everywhere and doesn’t require being connected to a VPN, just to name a couple more benefits. In order to provision access, we usually setup end users with either a mapped drive or, more recently, with Azure Storage Explorer. There are numerous advantages to using Storage Explorer, in my opinion, but that’s not really the scope of this post. However, the ability to use an SAS (Shared Access Signature) URI is one that is relevant.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Azure Fundamentals Certification Preparation</title><link href="https://azurebrian.com/training/2020/03/31/AZ900-Prep.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Azure Fundamentals Certification Preparation" /><published>2020-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-31T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://azurebrian.com/training/2020/03/31/AZ900-Prep</id><author><name>Brian Davis</name></author><category term="training" /><category term="certification" /><category term="fundamentals" /><summary type="html">UPDATE: Today, 09-24-2020, I took and passed the AZ-900 exam. I wanted to revisit this post with my thoughts and impressions now that I can look back on the process. Of course, I can’t dive into specifics regarding the exam or the questions, but suffice it to say that I thought it was very fair. I have to say that the MeasureUp Practice tests prepared me very well. In fact, I think they were harder than the actual exam. So, I highly recommend using them. I also was struck by how much I fell back on what I had experienced by actually using Azure to deploy resources or just play around. So, I would definitely also say that any time you can spend in Azure deploying VMs, configuring resources, or just doing Microsoft Learn modules that allow you to use a sandbox, is well worth it. Furthermore, if you get Azure credits via a Visual Studio subscription through your company or otherwise, take advantage of them. It’s $150 in free money every month to play around and tinker! I also really appreciated being able to use Tim Warner’s study guide on specific topics I felt I needed reinforcement on. And Mike Pfeiffer’s Cloudskills.io podcasts are really good as well. In fact, these fellas have a one-day bootcamp coming up in October. So, if you’re thinking about starting your cloud journey by taking this exam, it’s a great time to do it. Good luck and please leave a comment below if you have any other helpful tips or resources!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Launch!!!</title><link href="https://azurebrian.com/general/2020/03/26/launch.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Launch!!!" /><published>2020-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-03-26T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://azurebrian.com/general/2020/03/26/launch</id><author><name>Brian Davis</name></author><category term="general" /><category term="blog" /><summary type="html">Greetings! I wanted to write a few lines to capture the milestone represented by this post – it’s the first one! I’m excited about what this means in terms of my journey in this space, but I do hope it will be a resource for others who are looking for good, helpful Azure-related content as well. Just a quick shout out to some of the folks that have inspired me to launch this blog:</summary></entry></feed>